字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
字幕出自 Netflix，提前 16 秒对应 BD Subtitles from Netflix, 16 seconds ahead for BD Netflixの字幕、BDは16秒先読 み
Thorkell must be behind this!
這一定是托魯克爾的詭計！
I can't think of anyone else.
除此之外我想不到別的了
But Lord Floki, the mesage from Derby said--
可是弗洛基大人
There are too few on the left! Don't underestimate 500 warriors!
左翼太少人了！
We're up against Thorkell!
那可是托魯克爾的軍隊！
Lord Floki, if the reports are true, doing this would be sedition.
弗洛基大人，萬一報告屬實 這樣做恐怕會很無禮…
Unbelievable.
不可能
To think Prince Canute would return home with Thorkell in tow.
那個庫奴特殿下 不可能將托魯克爾收為部下
It's inconceivable!
絕對不可能！
Hey, Floki!
喂，弗洛基！
Want to fight? I'll be your opponent.
想打一場嗎？我可以奉陪
Stand down, Thorkell.
托魯克爾，退下
I sent an envoy ahead of my arrival announcing my return home, Floki.
使者應該在幾天前
Are you greeting me with spears in hand?
你們居然持著長矛出來迎接？
No, I would never intend to do something so…
不…我絕對不會故意…
Askeladd!
阿謝拉特！
What are you doing here?
你怎麼會在這裡？
Have your ears stopped working?
你聾了嗎？
I am asking you if you intend to point your arrows
我在問你是不是打算
at a member of Danish royalty.
對丹麥王室動武
No, that's…
不是的…
We Jomsvikings
我們約姆戰士團
received a false report of an enemy army attack.
接到了敵軍來襲的錯誤情報
I am deeply sorry.
非常抱歉
Report back that I plan to visit the king's estate in the evening.
你去稟報國王陛下 我將在傍晚時去拜見
Be accurate.
說得準確一點
What the hell just happened?
到底是怎麼回事？
He's a completely different person.
他好像完全變了一個人
DANISH ARMY MAIN BASE GAINSBOROUGH CASTLE
（蓋恩斯伯勒城內 丹麥軍團大本營）
All of you. Walk with me and listen.
你們邊走邊聽
Today, we cannot start any fights.
現在還不能動手
I have few allies among these men.
這支軍隊裡支持我的人很少
Any provocation will make us traitors.
只要稍微反抗就會被視為叛徒
We need time to form a plan.
我們需要時間安排
Thorkell,
托魯克爾
you've betrayed them once, but you remain popular with the warriors.
雖然你背叛過他們
I want you to interact with the heads of each clan to restore relations.
你去和各部族的首領交涉，修復關係
Are you saying
你的意思是
you want me to go on a drinking binge at your expense?
你要請客讓我喝到爽嗎？
Ensure that the other leaders join. Go.
別忘了要邀請其他首領，去吧
What a terrific order!
這命令好棒！
I was right to follow you.
跟著你果然是對的
Let's go!
-走吧！ -喂！
Askeladd, come with me to see the king.
阿謝拉特，你跟我去見父王
I want your assessment of him.
我想聽你對他的看法
Understood.
遵命
How do you think we should proceed from here on out?
從現在開始，我們要怎麼做？
Well.
是
With limited time, assassination is preferable.
時間有限的情況下，暗殺會比較合適
Because your elder brother Prince Harald is far away in Denmark,
您的王兄哈羅德殿下正遠在丹麥國內
there is an opportunity.
這是個好機會
If the king met his demise now,
國王陛下若是現在駕崩
you would become commander-in-chief to the English field army.
英格蘭遠征軍的最高指揮官就是您了
Thorfinn,
托爾芬
from here on, you will serve as more than my protector.
從今以後，除了保護我 我還會派其他任務給你
I'm counting on you.
拜託你了
Don't order me around.
不要命令我
I don't recall agreeing to serve you.
我可沒答應要當你的手下
Please forgive his impertinence.
請原諒他的無禮
I'll relay your orders to this dolt.
我來下令給這個笨蛋
I wonder
不曉得
if God
神是否正看著我們
Losing friends, parents and children killing each other…
失去朋友、父子相殘
God is watching us commit these acts from high up in the heavens.
神高坐在天堂俯視這一切
I'll never forgive him.
我絕不原諒祂
I will take this land and turn it into a paradise.
我要把這片土地變成樂園
It will be peaceful, abundant,
和平又富饒
and the ideal land for those who suffer in life.
為那些受苦的人們建立一個理想國度
It may not happen in my generation,
或許在我有生之年無法實現
but I will take the first step.
但我還是會踏出第一步
God will surely call me to his side with love.
神一定會眷顧我，召喚我到祂的身邊
However,
不過
when that happens, I will say,
那時候我會對祂說
"We have no need of the Kingdom of Heaven or its trials.
“我們不需要天堂和試煉了
Our paradise is here
人間就有樂園”
We will regain what we have lost.
我要奪回我們失去的東西
If I must become a demon to attain this goal. So be it.
為達目標，我就算變成魔鬼也無所謂
I will assist you,
我會助您一臂之力
Your Highness.
殿下
I am pleased you have returned.
你終於回來了
I am happy,
我很高興，庫奴特
I'm grateful for your words.
謝謝父王
I am unworthy of them having lost the soldiers you placed under my command.
孩兒不才 父王交給我的軍隊全數陣亡了
Come closer.
你過來
Hold on.
請等一下
Your assessment, Thorfinn?
托爾芬，你覺得怎樣？
They're here.
有人
About 20 men.
大約20個
There are also archers in the rafters.
高處也有弓箭手
Your Highness,
殿下
it is an ambush.
有埋伏
It seems the king has already made up his mind as to how to proceed.
看來國王陛下看出我們的意圖了
What's wrong?
怎麼了？
Do you hesitate to approach?
怎麼不快點過來？
You two, no matter what happens, do not draw your swords.
你們兩個聽好 不管發生什麼事都不能拔劍
The first to draw his sword will lose.
誰先動手就輸了
This is
這就是那樣的較量
My eyes have adjusted to the dark.
眼睛適應黑暗了
A little closer, and I'll be able to see the king's face.
再靠近一點就可以看到國王的臉
If I can see his face…
只要看到臉…
Halt.
停下來
That's close enough.
夠近了
Kneel.
跪下
He has tired eyes.
他的眼神很疲累
So this is the king of the Danes?
這就是丹麥人的國王？
Askeladd.
阿謝拉特
What happened to Ragnar?
拉古納爾怎麼了？
I do not see him with you.
我沒看到他
He died in Mercia.
他死在麥西亞了
I see. That is regrettable.
這樣啊
He was a most sincere and loyal retainer.
他是個忠臣
In a normal situation, we would be toasting your return with food and drink.
照理說應該設宴慶祝你平安歸來
However, I would like
但我不想拘泥於形式 我想直接和你談談
Canute only, rise.
庫奴特，站起來
Take ten steps forward.
向前走十步
In such a short time,
這麼短的時間內
your face has changed.
你的神情都變了
You look like I did in my youth.
很像我年輕的時候
Then
那麼您應該知道我內心的想法吧
A burdensome child.
真是麻煩的孩子
To think our likeness is so true even in this regard.
竟然連這點都這麼像我
Children
孩子都是看著父母長大的
You mustn't blame yourself.
您不能責怪我
When I was young,
我年輕的時候
I drove my father, the late king, out of the country
也是將我的父親 也就是先王逐出王國
and I took this crown for myself.
奪走了這頂王冠
I did it because I believed it was for the good of the kingdom.
我這麼做是因為 我相信這是為了王國好
Although, he was by nature cruel and a coward.
先王天性殘忍，但卻膽小懦弱
The world would be chaotic if a man like that wore the crown.
那種人戴上王冠會造成世界大亂
How can he say that when he's protected on all sides?
你四周都有護衛，還敢說別人膽小？
Silence. He can hear you.
閉嘴，他聽得到
You've decided against asserting yourself by force, Your Highness?
您不打算展現自己的威力嗎，殿下？
Don't forget you're in the lion's den now.
別忘了您現在身處敵境
I thought I did a good deed.
我以為自己做了好事
I believed I would bring prosperity,
我以為自己能造福人民
until I put this on.
直到我戴上這頂王冠
This crown on my head
這頂王冠有自己的意志
Once you wear it, you command 1,000 ships and 10,000 warriors.
戴上它就能統帥千軍萬馬
You can have any of the treasures retrieved from distant lands.
能到遙遠國度帶回豐富寶藏
You can feel a godlike power inside you.
你能擁有如神一般的力量
However…
但是…
However, Canute,
但是，庫奴特
it is not the king who wields this power.
運用這股力量的並非國王
This power is ruled by the will of the crown.
而是王冠本身的意志
Are you saying then it was the crown who gave the order
您的意思是，是王冠下令
to have me killed?
要殺我的嗎？
There are only two things the crown wants from the king.
王冠只會命令國王做兩件事
To use power and to increase power.
運用力量和增強力量
It is futile to fight it.
反抗也沒有用
And the crown does not want you.
王冠不想要你
Canute,
庫奴特
I will grant you dominion of Cornwall.
我會給你康沃爾一部分的領土
There you may read the Holy Bible and spend your days in tranquility.
你可以在那裡讀聖經 過著安穩的生活
If you refuse me now,
如果拒絕，那你就死在這裡
Is the crown forcing you to say those words, Your Majesty?
這些話也是王冠告訴你的嗎，陛下？
Your Majesty!
陛下！
Forgive my intrusion, but I ask for permission to speak.
斗膽請陛下允許我發言
State your name.
報上名來
I am Prince Canute's retainer,
我是庫奴特殿下的隨從
son of Olaf, Askeladd.
沃拉夫之子阿謝拉特
Pardon me, but will your commands fulfill the will of the crown?
冒昧請問這命令 真的出自於王冠的意志嗎？
Continue.
繼續說
His Highness took Thorkell's army from London and put it under his command.
王子殿下成功地從倫敦 奪取了托魯克爾的戰力
the city will have no choice but to surrender.
倫敦只有投降一途
The riches of London will be yours without exception.
陛下不費一兵一卒 就能得到倫敦的財富
The one whose sacrifices ensured this favorable outcome
付出重大犧牲帶來如此戰果的
is none other than Prince Canute.
正是庫奴特殿下
What is the logic of punishing the man who accomplished this deed?
取得這般功績的人 卻遭到處罰的道理何在？
These commands may worry your generals
在分配新領地之前
when it is time to divide the new territory.
這樣的命令會造成將軍們的不安
I beg you to reconsider.
懇請陛下三思
You're a well-spoken man.
你還真會說話
Askeladd.
阿謝拉特
"Of the ashes," huh?
“滿身灰塵”的意思？
That is only an epithet.
那只是外號吧
Tell me the name your father gave you.
你父親替你取的名字是什麼？
It is only Askeladd.
就是阿謝拉特而已
My father did not give me a name.
我的父親並沒有替我取名字
A bastard from his mistress?
你是妾所生的嗎？
No.
不是
You were born to a slave.
是奴隸生的吧？
What?
什麼？
I've never seen Askeladd so enraged.
我第一次看到阿謝拉特這麼生氣
Canute,
庫奴特
you have brought an astute retainer.
你這個隨從很不錯
It's just as he said.
他說得沒錯
I should reward you and your men.
我應該好好獎勵你們
Tomorrow, I will depart for York.
我明天將前往約克
There, a banquet will be prepared.
我將在那裡設宴
I will grant you your reward there.
到時候我會賜獎賞給你
I was scared to death, Your Highness.
我快嚇死了，殿下
What is there to be worried about?
有什麼好擔心的？
As you rightly presumed,
你想得沒錯
the king has no good reason to kill me now.
國王現在沒有殺我的正當理由
He wishes to be called a wise king.
他想被稱為賢君
As long as we aren't rash, it's safer to stay close to him.
只要我們不輕舉妄動 待在國王身邊反而更安全
All the more reason to refrain from provoking him as you did now.
那您就不應該像剛才那樣挑釁國王
That won't be a problem.
那不成問題
King Sweyn is a slave to his crown.
斯韋恩王只是王冠的奴隸
I will show him
我會讓他知道該如何駕馭王冠
Askeladd?
他叫阿謝拉特嗎？
I should be careful and treat him with caution.
這個人必須小心提防
Drink up!
-乾杯！
Come on, drink to your heart's content! Prince Canute is indulging us!
盡情地喝吧！
Long live the prince!
殿下萬歲！
That's his 57th drink!
這是他的第57杯！
What a beast!
他簡直是怪物！
Hey, man who's been swigging one drink after another,
喂，不停灌酒的人
who are you?
你是誰啊？
I don't recall inviting a monk.
我不記得有請神父來啊
I'm Willibald. Have you forgotten me?
我是威里巴多，你不記得我了？
Huh?
-什麼？
The bearded one?
留鬍子的那個？
-He's so young! How old are you? -Twenty-three.
他好年輕，你幾歲？
-No way! -He's in his early twenties?
-不會吧！ -他才20幾歲？
All right, I'll go against you next!
好，下一個換我跟你比！
It's the commander's turn!
換老大了！
He's already had 58 drinks.
他已經喝58杯了！
He's a strange man.
他真是不可思議
Yes.
是啊
So, how goes it?
怎麼樣？
Do you think you can
你覺得你殺得了國王嗎？
It will certainly
我必須說這不簡單
By the look of him, he is smart.
光看就知道他很聰明
He possesses insight and the will to make the first move.
他有敏銳的洞察力 和先下手為強的行動力
If he sees us contravening his authority, he will make his next move.
要是看到我們無懼於他的威脅 他會立刻改變戰術
I would say he's skilled in battle.
看得出他驍勇善戰
I suppose that is why he is the king of the land.
或許那就是他成為一國之王的原因
He is a formidable foe.
他會是個難纏的對手
Even if we could kill him, we cannot do it now.
就算要殺他，也不能現在動手？
In the meantime, while we consider his vulnerabilities,
現在暫時先假裝順從
we must play the part of loyal subjects.
一邊觀察他的弱點
Your Highness!
殿下！
I am overjoyed at your safe return.
您平安歸來，真是太好了
You cannot imagine how worried Gunnar has been!
您知道君納爾我有多擔心嗎？
Forgive me for not receiving you upon your return to the castle.
您抵達城堡時，很抱歉沒能前去迎接
After all, I myself just returned from a foreign land.
畢竟我剛從國外回來
Of course, I always knew you'd return home safely.
當然，我一直相信您會平安歸來
What's this? Is this gentleman your new retainer?
這位是您的新隨從嗎？
May I be introduced to him?
能否介紹我認識認識？
This is Ragnar's younger brother Gunnar. Introduce yourself.
他是拉古納爾的弟弟君納爾 打聲招呼吧
I am the son of Olaf, Askeladd.
我是沃拉夫之子阿謝拉特
Oh my, you seem very reliable.
你看起來很可靠
I am Gunnar.
我是君納爾
By the way, Your Highness,
對了，殿下
regarding our old plan it seems our prospects have improved.
我們之前計畫的那件事有希望了
The Duchy of Normandy.
諾曼第公國那件事
I'd like to speak with you and my brother about it later.
我稍後再與您和拉古納爾大哥談談…
Ragnar has died.
拉古納爾死了
I'm sorry for the trouble you must have taken.
很抱歉你費心替我做了這麼多安排
Also, I will not go into exile.
不過我不會逃往國外
Your Highness…
殿下，您說什麼…
I know that traveling to all those countries was difficult.
你為我奔走各國，辛苦了
I just had a confrontation with King Sweyn.
我剛才去挑釁斯韋恩王了
-I'd like you to lend a hand. -Ragnar is…
-我想請你幫忙 -拉古納爾…
Gunnar.
君納爾
Your job is to watch the king and report back to me.
你負責監視國王 並向我報告他的動向
Choose useful men whom you can trust.
選出值得信任的手下
Your Highness! You mustn't speak of that in a place like this.
殿下，在這種地方 談論這種事不太好吧
Don't worry.
無所謂
This place is the perfect cover.
這種地方反而適合密談
Your Highness.
殿下
You have changed.
您變了
I have.
是的
And I must change everything else.
我必須改變一切
That Gunnar could be a problem.
那個君納爾可能會是問題
I don't think he's as loyal to the prince as he let's on.
我不認為他如殿下說得那麼忠心
You're certainly devoted to your preparation.
你還真拚命
Your right arm is healing well.
右手應該不痛了吧
Askeladd.
阿謝拉特
I see.
這樣啊，你們要回家鄉了？
I know you said you don't care, but we're still traitors to you.
雖然你說不在意
I don't know how we could ever face you again.
該怎麼說呢 我不知道以後該怎麼面對你
That hurt!
好痛！
That's right! I got you!
好耶，打中了！
And now that my brother is like this…
我哥現在也變成那個樣子了
I hope Bjorn's injuries heal.
希望表倫的傷勢能痊癒
Atli, how can you call yourself a Viking after saying all that?
亞托利，你這樣還能自稱維京人嗎？
How did an honest man like you ever become my lackey?
你這種人是怎麼成為我手下的？
Bjorn won't last much longer.
表倫撐不了多久了
The wound spread to his bowels.
他傷到了內臟
Soon, Thorfinn will be the last man from the old crew.
這下子以前的手下就只剩托爾芬了
It's the perfect time for a fresh start.
正好適合重新開始
Your bracelet?
你的手環？
It's gold. Take it.
是金的，拿去吧
What? I can't! I have no reason to!
什麼？我不需要！ 我沒有收下它的理由！
Just accept it.
你就收下吧
You can never have too much gold on your travels.
多帶點金子上路總是方便
I'm sorry.
對不起
Then, with grate gratitude…
那我就不客氣…
Huh? What?
什麼？
What the hell?
搞什麼？
Are you giving it to me or not?
你到底要不要給我？
I have a condition.
我有個條件
Never wield a sword again.
永遠不要再揮劍了
It doesn't suit you, Atli.
你不適合拿劍，亞托利
Buy some sheep, take a wife, raise kids, and die in your bed.
養一些羊、娶個老婆 生幾個孩子，老了就死在床上
If I ever see you on a battlefield again, I'll kill you, even if you're my friend.
如果以後在戰場上看到你 就算我們站在同一邊，我也會殺了你
Yes.
好
I understand.
我知道了
What is that?
那是什麼？
What is it?
這個嗎？
It's something precious.
很寶貴的東西
That's a high price! Lower it!
太貴了，算便宜一點！
-Bring out a younger woman! -A younger woman!
-帶個年輕一點的出來！ -年輕的！
Anyone want her? She's a fine beauty!
有人要她嗎？她很漂亮！